John Gedeon

Creative, agile and innovative Staff Software Engineer and Project Leader with over 17 years experience in a variety of languages and technologies. A track record of designing, building, and implementing complex and flexible systems from a user centered approach.

johnw (at) gedeons.com github.com/gidjin linkedin.com/in/gidjin

EXPERIENCE

TrussWorks, Remote — *eApp - DISA*

September 2018 - March 2019

https://github.com/18F/e-QIP-prototype

eApp is a project sponsored by the <u>Defense Information System Agency</u> to create a new modern applicant portal for filling out clearance background check forms. As the project lead for Truss, I was responsible for technical decisions for the front end, code reviews of work from teammates, and providing architectural recommendations and documenting decisions and what options were considered.

QualApps, Sacramento, Ca. — Ursus - CA DOJ

April 2018 - September 2018

California Department of Justice (DOJ) uses Ursus to collect law enforcement use of force data as part of the <u>OpenJustice</u> initiative. I was responsible for maintenance and enhancements to the existing software, as well as resolving performance issues. The project used **Ruby on Rails**, **Sidekiq**, **JQuery**, **Docker Swarm**, **MongoDB**, **Elasticsearch**, Git, and **Redis**.

Primarily I handled resolving technical debt, architecting the application for high availability by deploying across multiple nodes, and training state employees in software engineering best practices and maintenance of the Ursus software.

CaseCommons, Sacramento Ca. — California Child Welfare Digital Service

April 2017 - February 2018

https://github.com/ca-cwds/intake

As a developer on the Case Commons team working on California's Child Welfare Digital Service (CWDS) intake project, I built rich user-centered open source application with modern technologies such as **Ruby on Rails**, **Redux**, and **React**. I worked with CWDS Technology Platform teams to define API contracts, as well as implement and test corresponding API endpoints. Also coordinated with Product Owners and UX Designers to refine, estimate, and deliver stories as part of an agile (**Scrum**) process within a Scaled Agile Framework (**SAFe**). Integrated engineering best

SKILLS

Software Development

Agile Methodologies

Test Driven Development

Git Source Control

Linux Administration

Functional Programming

Object-oriented programming

Services

Docker

High Availability

LANGUAGES

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, Java, Scala, Play Framework, Go

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

California Polytechnic State University

San Luis Obispo, Ca

practices including test-driven development (TDD), continuous integration (CI), pair programming, and user research to deliver features.

StreamSend, Sacramento Ca. — *Insights Product*

August 2015 - March 2017

Insights is a marketing automation product that allows companies to automate targeted advertising campaigns to their customers. It integrates with company websites and software via a simple to use RESTful API, and has a user interface for configuration and reporting. Technologies used included: Scala, Akka Actors, RESTful APIs, Cassandra, AngularJS, Bower, JenkinsCI, Docker, Git, and Node. We used best practice agile development methods to deliver new features and functions to end–users. Integrated with various APIs both internal and external such as SendGrid.

I introduced **Docker** and containerized our project to improve local development, build process, and consistency with the continuous integration system

StreamSend, Sacramento Ca. — *Email Marketing Product*

April 2014 - August 2015

Worked as part of the core infrastructure team supporting StreamSend's SAAS email marketing tool are related services. I handled resolving bugs, reducing technical debt, and general software maintenance. I developed various automated scripts to improve efficiency and stability of the release process. Implemented features to extend functionality based on the needs of new and existing customers. Technologies used include <code>AngularJS</code>, <code>Ruby</code> on <code>Rails</code>, <code>MySQL</code>, <code>Git</code>, and <code>RESTful</code> APIs.

eBay, Sacramento Ca. — X.commerce Product

September 2011 - March 2014

X.commerce was a greenfield project put on by eBay. While on the team I developed various marketplace adapters designed to communicate with eBay and Amazon marketplaces via RESTful APIs using a custom common commerce messaging platform. I developed a custom test framework to facilitate the creation of unit and functional tests for a multi-threaded system with the ability to simulate multiple clients. I mentored the team in open source technologies, methodologies, and best practices. I participated in various agile ceremonies including acting as scrum master for a time. Technologies included: Java, Spring, MongoDB, Maven, Mockito, TestNG, RESTful APIs, SVN, Git, GitHub, and Akka.

HOBBIES

I enjoy watching movies, photography, playing games, camping, working on electronics, and doing those things with my family and friends.